从早期的太空飞行开始火箭发射就一直很壮观
Ever since the early days of space-flight, rocket launches have been a fascinating spectacle
即使到了现在，火箭升空仍然是发射中最一颗赛艇的环节
Up until recently, lift-off has usually been the most tense and exciting part of any launch
但当太空叉横空出世，开始搞火箭回收
But ever since SpaceX came along and started to re-use their rockets
人们的目光开始更多地聚焦在猎鹰九号一级着陆上
the landing of the Falcon 9 booster has become one of the most iconic shots in spaceflight
当我们观看直播的时候就就就就就
that is, when we get to see it
可惜，我们发现太空叉的直播
Sadly, when watching the SpaceX broadcast
经常会在火箭着陆前几秒卡顿，留给大家无尽悬念
the live video feed often cuts out just as the rocket is coming into view, leaving us in suspense
那这是为什么呢？
But why does this happen?
本期视频，我们将了解太空叉如何获取着陆区的视频直播流
In this video we are going to look at how SpaceX broadcasts live video from their landing sites
并了解火箭是如何导致直播中断的
We’re also going to look at how the live feed is interrupted by the rocket
以及应对此现象的可能的解决办法
and the possible solutions that could be put in place to get around this problem
猎鹰九号一级火箭回到地球的时候，它要么落回陆地的着陆场
When the Falcon 9 lands back on Earth, it will either land back near the launch site
要么落在几百英里外大洋中的拖船上
or on a drone-ship placed hundreds of miles out in the ocean
想要从如此遥远位置的拖船传送直播数据，只能使用卫星
With the drone-ship being in such a remote location the live video feed has to be transmitted via satellite
船上一个大天线直接把信号发给卫星
A large antenna on the drone-ship sends a directional signal towards the satellite
原视频的小错误，这卫星是GOES系列的气象卫星，不是通信卫星(-_-#)
该卫星介绍见av20451601
卫星之后把数据转发给地面的直播团队
which will then transmit that footage back down to the broadcast team
左边是定向天线 右边是全向天线
船上天线必须是定向的，否则到达卫星的信号强度不够
The signal from the drone-ship needs to be directional, in order for it to be strong enough to reach the satellite
于是当火箭接近拖船时就有问题了
The problem occurs when the rocket gets close to the drone-ship
火箭准备着陆时，它会使用1台或3台梅林发动机
As it comes in for a landing, the rocket is slowed down using either 1 or 3 of it’s
这个推力数值貌似是节流后的
每台推力十万磅力（45吨），一起向拖船喷火
Merlin engines each firing over 100,000lbs of thrust towards the surface of the drone-ship
火箭离船越来越近时，火箭的推力会让船摇晃
As the rocket gets closer to the drone-ship, the thrust from the engines start to shake the drone-ship
频率很高，会让天线失去对卫星的锁定，导致直播中断
with such a high frequency that the video feed antenna loses lock with the satellite, causing the video feed to cut out
当火箭着陆停稳，震动消失，直播就恢复了
Once the rocket has landed and the vibrations have dissipated, the video feed should reappear
在这段时间，画面仍然会在拖船本地保存
During this period of time, the footage is recorded
并在拖船恢复与卫星连接后马上补发
and will be sent back as soon as the drone-ship regains connection with the satellite
这样做不但可以让工程师对每次着陆进行分析
Not only does this ensure that the engineers can analyze each landing
还能让太空叉在直播后上传完整录像供大家观看
it also means that SpaceX can upload the footage after the broadcast for everyone else to watch
具体解决办法有很多
There have been many solutions put forward to fix this issue
一种办法是在几百米外再放一个小船
One solution would be to have a similar ship placed a few hundred metres away from the
视频信号通过小船上天线与卫星连接
drone-ship with it’s own antenna to transmit the video feed
这样小船不会受到震动影响，缺点是它必须和拖船之间
This antenna ship would be unaffected by the vibrations but it would need to be connected
使用非常长的视频线连接来传递数据
to the drone-ship using a very long video cable to receive the footage
当然线缆可以用全向天线代替
A way around this is to transmit the video feed from the drone-ship using a non directional
相当于使用小船再做一次直播数据的中继
signal to the antenna ship, which would then transmit the video feed up to the satellite
从而避免受到火箭着陆时带来的震动
without being interrupted by the rockets vibrations
尽管太空叉解决这种小问题SO EASY
Although this may seem like a problem that SpaceX could easily fix
但这还要给整个回收过程增加一条船
going through the effort of adding more vessels to their recovery fleet
只为了流畅地看那么几秒的直播，有点不太值得
doesn’t seem like it’s worth the cost for just a few seconds of live video
而且即使我们在着陆时看不到流畅的画面，那些画面也会被记录下来
Even if we don’t get to see live footage of the landing, the footage is always recorded
并且在几天后上传给大家看
and uploaded a few days later for all of us to see
失败集锦av14923456
即使着陆失败
even when the landing goes wrong
因此尽管在回收最一颗赛艇的时候画面卡一下的确挺揪心
So while it may be frustrating to lose the video feed right at the most exciting part of each mission
但太空叉火箭回收的转播工作做的其实已经非常到位了
it does seem like SpaceX do everything they can to eventually bring us clear footage of each landing
如果你对太空叉如何转播发射还有什么问题
If you have any more questions on how SpaceX broadcast their launches
欢迎在评论区讨论
let me know in the comments below
如果愿意资瓷YouTuber “Primal Space”
If you enjoyed this video and would like to become one of the first contributors to Primal Space
也欢迎去下面的链接里资瓷
please visit patreon.com/primalspace
最后字幕翻译给虫，欢迎点赞投币收藏分享关注
And as always, make sure you’re subscribed so you can join the discussion as we continue
一起提高致己的姿势水平
to learn more about all things space
感谢观看，下期见
Thank you very much for watching and I’ll see you in the next video